

# Lucas Stahl

#### Libertyville, IL | Stahl1109@gmail.com

# **Marketing Manager**

Ten plus years of experience working in marketing, sales and business development. Demonstrated ability to market new product/service lines and generate revenue. Territories encompassed the entire Chicagoland market. Self-starter, resourceful, logical and creative problem solver.

# **EDUCATION**

- Southern New Hampshire University- Master's Degree in Communications: New Media and Marketing (August 2017)
- Illinois State University- Bachelors of Arts and Science, Major in Communications (May 2006)
- Northwestern University- Web Programming Certificate (Expected May 2018)

ı			111	101	IT.	$\cap$	SKI	1.1	0
I	п	יטו	пь	احا۔	7 I	UГ	ONI	ᄔ	_ 🔾

Excellent project management Exceptional communication skills

Effective relationship builder Strong work ethic/professional demeanor

Experience in strategic planning Customer service centered

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Responsive Design, Git, JSON, jQuery, AJAX, Github, Firebase, Project Management, Windows, Mac, Microsoft Office, Design, Editing, Social Media, Blogging, Film editing (Premiere & Final Cut Pro), Adobe PDF, InDesign, Lightroom, Dreamweaver, Photoshop, WordPress, Salesforce and Workfront.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Northwestern Medicine Lake Forest Hospital - Lake Forest, IL

Senior Marketing Specialist

(08/15 - Present)

- · Project managed and developed marketing growth initiatives for orthopedics, neurosciences, pulmonary and cardiovascular service lines.
- Managed media marketing/advertising campaigns including social media tactics for Facebook.
- · Digital marketing lead for north region, including email marketing, web content, SEO, Google Analytics and design.
- Managed marketing budgets for hospital based service lines, exceeding a guarter million.
- Designed and edited consumer facing material through Adobe Software (InDesign, Photoshop, and Illustrator) in addition to video production (Premiere).
- · Developed and managed communications for new product/service launches and brand campaigns.
- Project lead for sponsorships including BMW Championship, with a budget over \$150k.
- Increased overall hospital brand awareness and achieved targeted service line ROI.
- Digital lead for new hospital activation, specifically the launch of the new Lake Forest Hospital.
- Worked cross-functionally with digital, internal communications and media/public relations teams to coordinate B2B or B2C growth.

#### Physician Services Outreach Representative

(04/12 - 08/2015)

- Developed initiatives and successfully increased referrals in areas of oncology, neurology, primary care, orthopedics, sports medicine, pulmonary, ENT, rehabilitation, imaging/diagnostics, medical devices, lab, and women's health.
- Facilitated physician-to-physician networking between employed physicians and private physicians to gain referrals.
- Ambassador for the Philanthropy department to raise funds for charitable organizations.
- Hosted networking events for both employed physicians and private physicians.



# Lucas Stahl

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE CONT'D

Odyssey Hospice Care - Arlington Heights, IL

Account Executive

- Built relationships with long term care facilities and physicians resulting in referrals.
- Developed and secured 19 additional multilevel contracts with facilities and hospitals in 2011 generating referrals and new revenue to the terri-
- Managed & directed the clinical team for ventilation patients.
- Increased referral base from averaging 1-3 patients per month in 2010 to 9-12 patients per month in 2011.

### Vitas Innovative Hospice Care - Chicago, IL

Sales Representative

(08/2009 - 11/2010)

(11/2010 - 04/2012)

- Developed and implemented quarterly sales plans.
- Increased referral base in a very challenging territory from 1-2 patients per month in 2009 to 5-7 patients per month in 2010.
- Developed and secured 10 new contracts which tripled referrals and had a significant impact on revenue.

#### Physiotherapy Associates, Inc. - Chicago, IL

Marketing and Sales Representative

(02/2007 - 08/2009)

- Designed and implemented a local lead generation program resulting in significant new referral source relationships and \$600,000 in additional annual revenues.
- Developed and implemented strategic annual marketing plans for 23 facilities with annual revenues of \$12 million.
- Managed staff in all phases of marketing, sales, budgeting and monthly goals.
- Worked with operations to review profit and loss statements.
- Increased physician referral base by 10% over a two-year period.
- Website design, content management and events coordinator.

Patient Services Manager (12/2005 - 02/2007)

www.lucasstahl.com

linkedin.com/in/lucasstahl



@LucasStahl11



github.com/Stahlwalker